squeeze i'll be honest i don't remember
what i put on this item frame i'm sure
it doesn't matter are there any
facilities on this thing i'm
kind of busting right now i have i have
a torch does that help press the buttons
wait a minute and we turn three times
one
two
three
oh
what
um
boys i'm on one heart and it says
minecraft alpha in the top left-hand
corner of my screen oh you're also steve
so are you dude
oh my gosh um
yeah
no this was neither of your fault i'm
gonna put my hands up this is uh yes my
bad
i remember you distinctly saying i'm
gonna flick some levers turn this three
times everything's gonna be okay
green i remember him saying i'm not sure
what goes in this item frame oh it
probably doesn't matter i remember that
this is something i remember it might
have been i think it was the compass the
compass is a big part of the time oh no
but there's an even bigger problem
not only are we in alpha this is i guess
this is what hermitcraft looked like if
it was in alpha um
that the time machine was entirely made
out of blocks that don't exist
so
it's vanished
wait it's completely vanished okay that
means we're stuck here forever
we can make um we can make one we can
make another time machine an impromptu
one but uh we're gonna have to start
from scratch there's no quartz in this
game there's no iron trap doors there's
no end rods there's no beacons there's
nothing i've got a new introduction to
hello everybody and welcome to
hermitcraft season minus 14.
[Laughter]
the prehistoric time forgot
i'm gonna go punch some trees gentlemen
because the sun is going down and for
those of you people out there don't know
what about alpha there's no sleeping
punching trees the old school way oh and
of course it's going to be nighttime and
nighttime in alpha
is just pure darkness you can't see
anything so good luck guys
oh man you guys gonna let me in guys get
into the tickets
don't know about you guys but it's a
little bit cramped
it's a little bit dark
and i don't like it
guys this is the authentic of minecraft
alpha experience okay you make a dirt
hut you sit in it until the sun comes up
yeah so we can actually open we can open
up
oh i'll get some moonlight yeah get some
moonlight actually it actually got a
little bit brighter yeah you guys are
looking really handsome
just like me
yeah you're looking handsome
oh thanks oh impulse you're looking
handsome we we're just three handsome
dudes right now yeah
the cult of steve do you know what the
best thing about alpha is
this sound effect
have three hearts oh dude come on
ah
light
oh it's day
yeah
i've been stuck in this hole for so long
i'm trying i'm trying to guys why is
this game so hard guys
what the heck
okay we're good oh man
nobody panicked that's the important
part
[Laughter]
okay gentlemen now that we've got light
i think we need a plan we need tools we
need coal we need torches
and
iron
i think i need they'll focus yeah
we've basically got to start from square
one all over again this is how you get
seeds ren this is how you get seeds back
in the day
oh there we go
oh wow 10 chance
nice here what you doing help me out
all right
boys i found some iron you're doing
doing good work
we need iron right is that gonna help
build the uh time machine back up
uh yeah iron it yep iron we're gonna
need we're gonna need diamonds we're
gonna need lots of diamonds um
this is gonna be a really
like haphazard time machine like
using some
dirty minecraft tricks i don't uh you
know i i wouldn't i think there's a 50
50 chance we're gonna die or delete our
account or something last time you said
50 50 chance it uh didn't go so well so
yeah it was 50 50. what do you expect
we're getting somewhere those torches
are doing nothing
they really are i don't know what's
going on
here torches are not crying but
not making any longer oh look there they
go
okay good um so i've started growing a
little bit of a crop field here
gentlemen i'm working on our house on
the beach you know i thought we could
have a villa to chill
yeah that's important yeah let's be
comfortable for sure and we've got a
little farm going we're professionals
i am going to make
the ultimate dirt alpha house guys
it's gonna it's gonna blow your mind oh
no ren this is disgusting
it's gonna be beautiful grian i don't
know what you're talking about man
please stop i'm gonna be glorious
i don't like it
you tend to the crops okay don't look
this way
what are you doing to my beautiful you
know how long it's going to take me to
take that down okay i can't be bothered
it's going to be a long time it's fine
this is going to be the worst house
that's ever been built
can i just say we are supposed to be
professional minecraft look at this
look at this the state of this place
[Applause]
i mean it's
this is terrible we're surviving badly
i've never been so happy to see the
sunrise if it it has been like 10 years
easily
yeah but i mean i made a cup of tea i
had a nap on the couch i mean there's a
lot of creepers we're actually kind of
getting ourselves semi-established at
the moment so
we need to start i tell you what i'm
gonna make a bunch of signs with
everything we're gonna need for this
makeshift time machine if we even have
signs in this version okay i think i've
got a list of everything we're gonna
need
we're gonna need some we're gonna need
one diamond block that's probably the
worst thing that we're gonna have to try
and find we need some wool fences a
clock some buttons iron blocks and a
compass as well
so we got to get our hands on quite a
few items fred
yes
come over here
check it out dude
hi
oh that's how you get rid of the trees
it's just gonna it's gonna go look how
fast it is oh my goodness look at that
is outrageously fast
um
well luckily our house is made out of
dirt cobblestone and sand yeah we won't
have this problem
yeah oh my goodness wow
i'm glad it's not like this anymore oh
yeah i think we're going to lose this
forest forever
uh we might lose the whole world
i think this fire is going to engulf
everything
could you imagine if if you made this on
hermitcraft you'd be kicked off the
server look at that i think so yeah
i'm quite proud of it though it's it's
got a certain an eclectic feel to it
it's got a nostalgic feel to it for sure
yeah i'm pretty sure if i set this floor
on fire ren the whole house goes up
green
don't you dare
did the buttons not exist
maybe they didn't i don't think so wow
no way
no they do exist they do exist brown put
some glass in the ceiling so we know
when it's day there we go how about one
here g you know completely like no
symmetry whatsoever of course none there
we go oh
yeah that this is an alpha house right
oh there we go oh this is great i think
i can get these so dark i can get
started on building some of the time
machine
really yeah i just need to get things
smelting and i'm gonna start putting it
together but we're gonna have to i think
all of us will need to go down and see
if we can find some diamonds soon okay
making the base for it nice
progress
yeah i don't like it i don't like it
it's been about six days
we are immediately already short of some
stuff so uh get digging get digging boys
let's get in there no wait there's a
crop ready i got it yes yeah
we've got one week
celebration i broke i broke two when
harvesting it
what whoa uh this is it back in alpha is
this an alpha thing oh my gosh
i thought it was just a
i thought it was just a troll
right it's a real thing
it's not a real thing
he just logged in
yeah but it was it was it was just a
myth
it was just one of those things that
people said oh yeah here brian's in my
world i saw him i swear
what does it do
nothing dude this is the first time i've
ever seen this
maybe he'll give us diamonds
maybe he's nice
i think i see him
really
really uh
um
are you guys definitely down in a cave
yeah down in the cave man all the way
down at diamond level yeah same here oh
[Music]
he must have known that you saw him
what no has that's ever been hacked
no what is happening
can we leave
that's what we're trying to do
yeah
[Music]
can you hurry up and get some diamonds
oh man working on it working on it oh
we might be able to make a bread
ah
hey bread we got our bread i told you
that bread we got a bread
we got this boys we're going to survive
now who who gets to eat this bread
you
yes
don't go for it there's no noise nothing
is just
gone diamond i left the safety of the
not instantly
house
oh whoops the safety of the house
there's a lot of bad things
we use safety in a relative term of
course i mean it's safer than this
i would say i'm running for it but i
can't run
gotta walk away
walk away walk away
speed walk is that a thing can you speed
walk power walk
power walk yeah
i made it
i'm not i'm not leaving the house it's
too dangerous
there's a creeper very near blue rocks i
found i found them
i'm on fire i'm on fire i found diamonds
yes
oh man they're beautiful
you're stealing my thunder dude i
invited you over to me because i also
have found
some diamonds it's about time you guys
found it
because the time
is almost finished oh wait you guys were
pretty close
you guys didn't go yeah there you are
no oh ren
yes hey fellas what's up
hi oh hi there okay so here's the chest
right there's the diamonds
right okay are we going back down wait
i'm going down for the first time we
need hit five diamonds and then we're
out of here five diamonds uh no okay i
found diamonds
did you sweet i found diamonds very nice
oh man is it a big a big bat two
three
four four diamonds
a couple extra to spare even there was
four five it's still going six this is
the best vein yet gonna get this i'm
gonna get this ready um this looks great
it's very primitive though yeah there's
not a lot of technology this is old
school
is this gonna work dude because it
didn't work last time i'm just saying
i don't know i honestly don't know well
it worked but maybe it worked too well
you could say because it took us way too
far back look at the old texture oh
there's the diamond block uh okay i can
mine this with a oh oh
oh no if you can't have
all right
let's go in
everyone
wait wait wait wait this world it's been
fun it's been fun let's go should we say
goodbye to the house
yeah see if we actually managed to make
any crops there's been a good house
don't take a picture of it i kind of
feel bad about what we did to this place
i don't
this is the best this place is a mess
this is very reminiscent of your
favorite your first minecraft world
right bread for ren bread for impulse
let's let's all eat it together as we're
going to say goodbye to this world
gentlemen we set the place on fire
killed all the animals
and
died a lot
let's get out of here yes
right i'm going to need one of you to
hold the compass because there's no item
frames i'm going to need one of you to
hold the clock
and you must hold them in your hand
that's absolutely essential it's still
the same tight squeeze it was before so
you must have built it right
uh hold hold on to those items for me
hit that button
okay hit that button
something's happening hit this button
[Music]
that was a rough landing where are we
false well we're in full swell
we're home wait we're home
dudes i've got it we've got an eye
lighters on we've got our skins back
yeah you're green again and you're
running the dog again
we're all a little less handsome though
speak for yourself speak for yourself
there buddy
[Laughter]
you know
this is not happening ever again this is
this was a disaster
and i won't stand for it uh
yeah i've got some tnt i've always got
some tnt
yeah i think it's time to put this thing
in the bin so to speak never
falling into anyone else's hands ever
again including including mine
oh there we go oh my goodness okay here
we go
we worked really hard for this diamond
block
we're gonna keep that
[Laughter]
took us about three hours to get that
block
yeah all right boys let's get back to
the hippie commune i need a nap i don't
know about you guys some beetroot oh
look at that oh you guys are just
showing up at the right time hey
what's the truth hey
hey
wait a minute can we come in yeah we
allowed it oh come on in guys oh oh geez
look at this we got a big announcement
for you gentlemen come on in step right
up it's a big audience we've got
refreshments in the course of disco yeah
what's good
they're very welcoming today
yes listen let the man speak please mr
uh angry eyes let them know
welcome
to area 77 park that is right we have
opened an amusement park of wonders and
amazing things currently we are
pre-ordering rides to the infinity
portal tell them doc about the infinity
portal yes the plays that take you can
take you to your dreams to anything you
desire infinite
possibilities
so yeah welcome and thanks for the high
pippies sorry hold up hold up
this isn't some sort of facility this is
part of hermit land
well
parts of it there's some very dangerous
things that you need to be careful with
that's why it is a secured ride an
amusement ride if you will think of
jurassic park you love jurassic park
copyright so yeah
are you sure the time machine's brought
us to the right herman crafted
i hope so
we just spent weeks
digging under this place to get the time
machine back
oh
why is that it's all over the place
um
not quite sure oh problems gotta bail
see you bye bye goodbye don't forget the
pre-order
you've gone goodbye
have a great time
don't forget to stop by
they kept that one quiet
yep careful for the creeper
so let me get this straight boys area 77
is now a theme park
yeah that's what we heard i think
i
was convinced that they had something
different up their sleeve i cannot
they've bamboozled us
they have led us astray they knew we
were making this area to to try and
infiltrate
and yeah they've just come out with this
and it was their plan all along
just let us do this
so many hours making massive mushrooms
flying rvs tunnels
just to be told that it was all a ruse
the whole time yeah
you're like such a fool
they got us guys i got i've got to give
credit to them they're absolutely we are
the ones that got bamboozled yeah yes
big time we were hippies for absolutely
no reason whatsoever i'm done i'm done
being a hippie that's it i think i
realize i renounce my hippie name
that's it i think yeah maybe we should
do exactly the same thing and pretend
like it was our our idea the whole time
we're going to turn this place into
hippie land and it's a free entry and it
was a it was a theme park the whole time
and um what do you mean pretend yeah
that was the plan yeah yeah yeah exactly
yeah
of course it was the plan yeah right
these costumes are just a facade exactly
you know
yeah yeah yeah i mean yeah i mean that
was our
idea isn't it to make hippy land and
absolutely
yeah yeah all right so why are we
protected why are we dressed like this
we should be dressed as businessmen as
we intended
that is better
have you stolen mumbo's clothes because
i've also done that in the past i i um
it was the closest thing i could find
yeah
i went to his closet and grabbed this
suit i hope he's okay with me borrowing
it
there's also something wrong with the
top of my head i think
i'm not sure is it i think it's a hat
yes i need to visit taylor green again i
think something
we all look apart though and uh together
we can open hippie land although we're
not very good businessmen we should
maybe charge one diamond entry um yeah
you know i i think this could work we
will just we'll play it off like this is
the plan the whole time
and then we'll slowly leave
and never come slowly
there's a bed and breakfast in shroom
town there's music festivals every
couple of weeks there's a flying rv
yeah
thing people are going to come from my
house i see this place yeah i think
it'll work it has been an incredible
journey but it looks like
i'm no longer
a hippie this part of my hermitcraft
experience
is over
this area is
pretty amazing and i kind of like how it
tells a story how we started with the
rvs
we made our own farm we've got all the
stuff underground the countdown the
giant rv the barn all of it and it's not
going to go to waste all of this stuff
will be extremely useful especially this
barn right here as it's going to produce
well sugarcane for all of my rocket
needs it's got a large amount of bone
meal all of the flowers because i want
to create more did you dye boxes
so it's pretty simple actually i just
have to craft up quite a lot of dyes
and then i fill up the shulker box with
those dyes rename them did you die boxes
and i can sell
any kind of die by mixing them together
very easily and also it looks like
there's a little chest here with a book
in
a gift
uh i just wanted to thank you for
allowing me to be part of hippie team i
hope my redstone skills came in handy
and i'm looking forward to watching your
redstone skills progress i have left you
a little gift to help along in that
department i hope you find good use for
the following redstone supplies feel
free to reach out with any redstone
related questions you may have along the
way your friend impulse that is so sweet
that is so sweet
how many he's given me how many
look at all these shulker
boxes look at this
oh my goodness there's so much stuff in
here
so much stuff
unbelievable
and there's even more
this is great
do you have any idea
how much this stuff is worth if i sold
all of these redstone components oh
that's a valuable box don't want to lose
that if i sold all of these boxes they'd
be worth hundreds of diamonds and that's
not an exaggeration hundreds of diamonds
in these shulker boxes i don't even know
what to do with them
oh i don't
to be honest i don't even know if i'm
gonna have much redstone to to do but
i'm gonna have to try and make something
now because this gift is absolutely
insane incredible and i love it i'm
gonna have to do something with it and
i've got to do something about my
storage like the shulker boxes are
spread everywhere i've even resorted to
just barrels of junk here like look
that's useful why am i storing really
valuable materials
in places i'm probably never gonna see
them again i've got to change my habits
somehow i've got to change my habits i
just saw impulses online so i said
impulse thank you so much he's in his rv
thank you so much for the redstone stuff
this is um this is insane i don't even
know what to do with all of this
oh man you bet buddy by the way did you
check out all the shulker boxes yet yeah
i did i checked them out he made me six
yeah i think so look at this yeah
pistons droppers
droppers dispensers
hoppers
oh okay then
redstone or
what
oh
no
yeah yeah maybe i did miss so yeah maybe
i did miss something
you sneaky you sneaky man
i thought i thought we were hippie
brothers
you sneaky i completely forgot about the
hot potato
i've i've been hot potatoed
by impulse
that is so that is a clever that is a
very very clever way of sneaking that
into my inventory
that was risky as well look at all this
stuff he made he has produced six
shulker boxes full of redstone stuff
just so i wouldn't see this
oh man i better see what the punishment
is you sneaky man
right what does it say i couldn't think
of a better person to pass this off to
other than the person that started the
game in the first place
for your punishment you must use a
resource pack of my choosing for an
entire episode this resource pack may or
may not make it a little more difficult
to navigate your sir oh man for an
entire episode
you can still keep the redstone
component oh well okay good at least i
get to keep this stuff but oh come on
all right i've got to keep the hot
potato on me
i'm really scared
i am terrified
i don't a whole episode with a mystery
resource pack that is
that's dangerous
well i think that's probably a really oh
yeah impulsive just
got me
well i think that's a really good place
to leave this episode so
thank you very much for watching i hope
you've enjoyed this episode and the
whole area 77 storyline i know i have
but it's time as my suit suggests to get
back to business
and looks like next episode's going to
be interesting because i've got the hot
potato punishment to do and i'm going to
pass it on to someone else so i'll see
you in the next episode and good bye
you